Let's go through an example scenario where we optimize some code to be more efficient.
来看一个示例场景 其中需要优化代码以提高效率
Say we're managing books for a store and we want to find
假设我们在管理商店的书籍
all the books published within the last two years about code.
想找到过去两年内发表的关于编程的所有书
We have a file that lists all the IDs of books published in the last two years,
我们有一个文件 列出了过去两年出版的所有图书 ID
called the books published last two years.txt.
叫做 books_published_last_two_years.txt
As well as a file for all Coding books, all_coding_books.txt.
同样还有一个所有编程书籍的文件 all_coding_books.txt
Since we want to find all the coding books published within the last two years,
既然我们想找到过去两年内出版的所有编程书籍
we'd want to find the book IDs included in both of these files.
也就是要找到这两个文件中共同包含的图书 ID
Your coworker came up with one approach and
你的同事想出了一种方法
shows you this code to find the books and both files.
向你展示了获取两个文件共有书籍的代码
After reading in the files,
读入两个文件后
their strategy is to loop through each book in the first file,
他们的策略是遍历第一个文件中的每本书
check if it's contained in the second file,
检查它是否包含在第二个文件中
and if so, add it to the final list.
如果是 将其添加到最终列表中
This makes sense and is an intuitive first approach.
这是可行的 是一种直观的方法
Let's see how long it takes to run.
让我们看看运行需要多长时间
So that took about 13.6 seconds.
花了大约 13.6 秒
There are several things we can do to make this more efficient.
我们可以有几种方式来提高效率
Here's some tips. First, use vector operations over loops when possible.
这里是一些提示 首先 尽可能使用向量运算而不是循环
Numpy and Pandas are your best friends for this.
Numpy 和 Pandas 是你最好的朋友
There are many cases in which you can replace loops with NumPy and Pandas
在很多情况下都可以使用 NumPy 和 Pandas 的函数替代循环
functions that use vector operations to make your computations a lot faster.
这些函数使用向量运算来使计算更快
Sometimes there's a method that does exactly what you need.
有时候可以找到对应的方法 完全满足需求
Other times, you need to be a little creative.
其他时候 你需要有点创意
This example in particular has a useful method you can use.
这个例子就有一个你可以直接使用的有用方法
Let me show you how I would approach this.
让我来展示一下我是如何找到的
No joke, I google.
不是开玩笑 我使用谷歌搜索
How to find common elements in two NumPy arrays,
如何在两个 NumPy 数组中找到共有元素
and here are the results I get.
这是我搜到的结果
Used NumPy's intersect 1d method to get
使用 NumPy 的 intersect1d 方法得到
the intersection of the recent books including books arrays.
recent_books 和 coding_books 数组的交集
I'll give you the same notebook and I'll put a cell right
我会给你相同的 Notebook 在这里放一个单元格
here with code to record the time it takes to run.
这里的代码记录运行所需的时间
Write your line of code in this line.
在这一行写下你的代码行
The second tip is to know your data structures and which methods are faster.
第二个提示是了解你的数据结构以及哪些方法更快
In addition to relying on Numpy and Pandas,
除了依赖 Numpy 和 Pandas 之外
it's often good to double-check whether there is a data structure or method
通常还需要仔细检查 Python 中是否存在
in Python that you can use to accomplish your task more effectively.
可用于更高效地完成任务的数据结构或方法
For example, in this case,
例如 在这种情况下
do you recall a data structure in Python that stores a group of
你还记得 Python 中的某种数据结构 可以储存
unique elements and can quickly compute intersections and unions of different groups?
一组不重复的元素 可以快速计算不同群组的交集和并集吗？
Sets. You can read more about why sets are more
那就是集合 你可以在本页底部提供的链接中
efficient than lists for this task in the link at the bottom of this page.
了解为什么集合比此任务中的列表更高效的信息
Also, remember how I said I Googled everything?
还记得我都是用谷歌搜索的这些吗？
Last time, I was Googling how to find common elements in specifically Numpy arrays.
上一次 我在谷歌搜索如何在特定的 Numpy 数组中找到共同的元素
But you can go even more general and Google something like,
但你可以搜索更加通用的关键词 比如
how to find common elements into lists Python and you'll
如何找到 Python 列表中的共有元素
see posts like this that share and compare different answers.
你会看到这样的帖子 分享和比较不同的答案
You can see the set being introduced here.
你可以看到这里介绍了集合
This seems to have a lot of votes but ultimately,
这个回答貌似有很多投票
we should try different methods and compare their efficiency for our example.
不过最终我们应该尝试不同的方法 比较它们在我们的例子中的不同效率
Because different methods perform differently in different contexts,
因为不同的方法在不同的情况中表现不同
it's smart to always test for yourself.
为自己的情况进行测试是最聪明的
In the next cell of the Jupyter notebook,
在 Jupyter Notebook 的下一个单元格中
find out how long it takes to compute the common elements of
看看使用 Python 集合的 intersection 方法
recent books and coding books using the Python sets intersection method.
计算 recent_books 和 coding_books 的共有元素需要多长时间
Here again is some code to measure how long it takes.
这里同样存在一些代码来计算代码运行时长